21stcenturywire.com 2019-12-17

# 21st Century Wire Privacy Policy - 21st Century Wire

This Privacy Policy describes how your personal information is collected, used, and shared when you visit [21stcenturywire.com](https://21stcenturywire.com/) (the “Site”).

This Privacy Policy only applies to the Site and does not apply to any embedded or integrated or linked third party “Services”, such as a plugin or other website linked to or from the Site. We are not responsible for the practices employed by these other Services, or the information or content contained thereon. Please remember that when you use a link to go from the Site to another website, our Privacy Policy is no longer applicable. Your browsing activity and interaction with any other website, including those that you link to or from the Site, is subject to that website’s privacy policy.

**PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

When you visit the Site, we automatically collect certain information about your device, including information about your web browser, IP address, time zone, and some of the cookies that are installed on your device. Additionally, as you browse the Site, we collect information about the individual web pages that you view, what websites or search terms referred you to the Site, and information about how you interact with the Site. We refer to this automatically-collected information as “Device Information.”

We collect Device Information using the following technologies:

  * **“Cookies”** are data files that are placed on your device or computer and often include an anonymous unique identifier. For more information about cookies, and how to disable cookies, visit [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).
  * **“Log files”** track actions occurring on the Site, and collect data including your IP address, browser type, Internet service provider, referring/exit pages, and date/time stamps.
  * **“Web beacons,” “tags,” and “pixels”** are electronic files used to record information about how you browse the Site.

> We use cookies to personalize content and ads, to provide social media features and to analyze our traffic for the benefit of our readers. You consent to our cookies if you continue to use our website.

Additionally, when you make a comment on a post through the embedded third party Disqus comment widget on the Site, the Service company Disqus, maker of the widget, will also collect certain information from you. Please refer to the [Disqus privacy policy](https://help.disqus.com/terms-and-policies/disqus-privacy-policy) for more details.

The Site links to a web form that collects email addresses for the purposes of sharing future content updates with its readers through a third party Service called MailChimp. Collection of this data is made on MailChimp’s Service. The Site does not collect this information directly, however, 21st Century Wire does have access to it securely on MailChimp’s Service. Please refer to the [MailChimp privacy policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/) for more details.

At various times, the Site will also embed other third-party Services, such as a chat widget, poll widget or survey widget. The same data collection terms apply as with the above stated.

When we talk about “Personal Information” in this Privacy Policy, we are talking about Device Information.

**HOW DO WE USE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

We use the Device Information that we collect to engage our readers in our content both on the Site and via email. It also helps us improve our Site and offerings by understanding our audience better. Embedded or integrated third party Services also use Device Information to optimize their Services and, in the case of advertising, deliver more targeted and relevant advertising to our audience.

**SHARING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

We do not share email addresses with third parties. We do share your Personal Information with third parties, through the embedded or integrated Services, to help us use these Services more effectively for the benefit of our Site users, as described above. For example, we use Google Analytics to help us understand how our readers use the Site – you can read more about how Google uses your Personal Information here: <https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>. You can also opt-out of Google Analytics here: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

Finally, we may also share your Personal Information to comply with applicable laws and regulations, to respond to a subpoena, search warrant or other lawful request for information we receive, or to otherwise protect our rights.

**ADVERTISING AND MARKETING**

As described above, we use your Personal Information, through third party Services, to provide you with targeted online advertisements or email marketing communications we believe may be of interest to you. For more information about how targeted advertising works, you can visit the Network Advertising Initiative’s (“NAI”) educational page at [http://www.networkadvertising.org/understanding-online-advertising/how-does-it-work](https://www.networkadvertising.org/understanding-online-advertising/how-does-it-work).

You can get more information about opting out of these programs directly by visiting these links:

<https://www.google.com/settings/ads/anonymous> _(No longer applicable to the Site)_  
<https://www.sovrn.com/privacy-policy/> _(No longer applicable to the Site)_

Additionally, you can opt out of some of these and other Services by visiting the Digital Advertising Alliance’s opt-out portal at: <http://optout.aboutads.info/>.

Specifically for email marketing communications, you can manage your MailChimp email subscriptions or opt-out at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link in the footer of any email you receive from us, or by contacting us directly at mail (at) 21stcenturywire (dot) com.

**DO NOT TRACK**

Please note that we do not alter our Site’s data collection and use practices when we see a Do Not Track signal from your browser.

21st Century Wire endorses the use of browsers that do not track your online activity. We recommend the [Brave browser](http://21w.co/brave) as an alternative for viewing the Site.

**YOUR RIGHTS**

If you are a European resident, you have the right to access personal information we hold about you and to ask that your personal information be corrected, updated, or deleted. If you would like to exercise this right, please contact us through the contact information below.

Additionally, if you are a European resident we note that we are processing your information in order to fulfill contracts we might have with you (for example if you make an order through the Site), or otherwise to pursue our legitimate business interests listed above. Additionally, please note that your information will be transferred outside of Europe, including to Canada and the United States.

**DATA RETENTION**

When you place an order through the Site, we will maintain your Order Information for our records unless and until you ask us to delete this information.

This includes collection of email addresses. As stated above, collection of this data is made on the third party MailChimp Service. The Site does not collect this information directly, however, 21st Century Wire does have access to it securely on MailChimp’s Service.

**CHANGES**

We may update this privacy policy from time to time in order to reflect, for example, changes to our practices or for other operational, legal or regulatory reasons.

**CONTACT US**

For more information about our privacy practices, if you have questions, or if you would like to make a complaint, please contact us by email at mail (at) 21stcenturywire (dot) com or by postal mail using the details provided below:

P.O. Box 410654  
Kansas City, MO  
64141  
USA
